Finding Aid for Gunnar Birkerts papers 1930-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Sports and Civic Stadium, Venice, Italy (unbuilt project), 1989-1992
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches of Facade. Undated, except as noted
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper with blue marker coloring, 10-3/4x12 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Green and black ink sketches on tracing paper with green and gray marker coloring, 12x11-1/4 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper with gray and blue marker coloring, 12x15-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, 2/9/92-2/11/92; Ink and red pencil sketches on four electrostatic prints, initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, 06/04/1992; Ink sketch with notations on white paper, 8-1/4x11-1/4 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, 06/09/1992; Black and red ink sketches on two sides of "Hotel Cavour, Milano" envelope with notations, 4x7-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Ink sketches on two sheets of "Hotel Londra & Cargill, Roma" memo pad, 5-1/2x3-1/2 inches, and letter paper, 8-1/4x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Ink sketch on electrostatic print of section, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Electrostatic print of sketch on steno pad paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Ink sketches on paper napkin, 11-3/4x11-3/4 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Red ink sketch on notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Ink sketches with blue marker coloring on four sheets of yellow tracing paper, 12x14-1/2 to 12x18-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Black and green ink and blue pencil sketches on eight sheets of white tracing paper, some with marker coloring, 12x11-3/4 to 12x44-3/4 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 6)
      - Schematic Design Drawings
        - [Elevations], untitled, 02/20/1992; Ink and red pencil drawing on blue-line print, initialed, 14-1/4x42 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - [Elevation], untitled, undated; Electrostatic print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - [Section], untitled, 06/13/1992; 06/14/1992; Ink and pencil drawings with blue, yellow and green marker coloring on two sheets of white tracing paper, initialed, 12x27 & 12x30-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
      - Design Development Drawings. Undated, except as noted
        - South and West Elevation, Red ink sketch on electrostatic print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - North and East Elevation, Red ink sketch on electrostatic print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - Bridge Plans, Elevation and Foundation Level Plan, Red ink sketches on electrostatic print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - North Side Wall Elevation and Typical Bridge Connection Area, 06/11/1992; Red and black ink sketch on electrostatic print, initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - [Axonometric of] Typical Bay, Precast Concrete Panel System, . Ink sketch on electrostatic print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - Photographic Prints of Above Five Drawings, 11-3/4x16-1/2-inch prints and six 10x12-inch negatives (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - Exterior Wall Plan/Section, North Side Wall Elevation, and Bridge Connection Area, Red and black ink sketches with yellow marker coloring on electrostatic print, 11-3/4x16-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - Sections, two untitled, Red pencil and pencil drawings on three electrostatic prints, 8-1/2x11 to 11x26 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
        - "Raggruppamento Temporaneo Di Imprese Per Lo Stadio Di Venezia.", Design presentation booklet including thirty-four electrostatic prints of plans, elevations and sections, 11-1/2x16-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 7)
  - University of Turin, Humanities Faculties Building, Turin, Italy (unbuilt project), 1989-1990
    - Project Files
      - Torino I
        - Program Information, 1988-1990 (Box 10)
        - Design Proposals (Box 10)
        - "Un Progetto Di Gunnar Birkerts A Torino,", 12/04/1989 (Box 10)
        - Correspondence and Transmittals, 5/23/88-5/9/90 (Box 10)
        - Newspaper and Journal Articles, 12/5/89-12/15/89 (Box 10)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches of Site Plan. Undated, except as noted
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with green marker coloring, initialed, 18x35 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper with green, brown and purple marker coloring, 12x30-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with gray and yellow marker coloring, 17-1/2x18 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with green, brown and purple marker coloring, 18x22-3/4 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, 06/30/1990; Digital image only of blue ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, with orange and blue marker coloring, 18x25-1/4 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x23-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x23 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Digital image only of ink sketch on tracing paper
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Digital image only of ink sketch on tracing paper
        - [Site Plan and Elevation], untitled, 10/19/1989; 11/05/1989; 07/27/1990; Five electrostatic prints of ink sketches, 8-1/2x11 inches, two dated 10/19/89 and 11/5/89, and one initialed and dated 7/27/90 (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan Studies], untitled, undated, 2/6/89, 06/30/1990; 07/01/1990; Blue, black and green ink sketches on thirty-two sheets of tracing paper with marker coloring, three initialed, 12x15-1/2 to 18x39-1/4 inches, two dated 2/6/89, one of each dated 6/30/90 & 7/1/90 (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Site Plan Study], untitled, 09/10/1989; Green and black ink drawing on tracing paper with colored pencil and marker coloring, initialed, 18x33-1/2 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, undated, 09/10/1989; 09/26/1989; 10/01/1989; Ink, colored marker, pencil and colored pencil drawings on four sheets of tracing paper, 18x31 to 18x38 inches, one sheet of vellum, 14-1/2x24-1/2 inches, and two electrostatic prints, 17-1/2x24 & 18x24 inches, four initialed and dated 9/10/89, 9/26/89, 9/30/89 & 10/1/89 (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - Presentation Drawings of Schemes-1/2, 1 and 2, Fourteen electrostatic prints of Site Plans and Sections, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
        - Presentation Drawings, Ink-on-vellum drawings, 32x48 inches
          - Site Plan (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
          - Basement One Floor Plan (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
          - Ground Floor Plan (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
          - First Floor Plan (Map-case 9, Folder 8)
      - Conceptual Sketches of Tower I. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketch], untitled, 09/06/1989; Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 18x21-1/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x22-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 09/06/1989; Digital image only of blue ink sketches on tracing paper, initialed
        - [Sketches], untitled, undated; 09/07/1989; Black, blue and green ink sketches on twenty-six sheets of tracing paper, four initialed, 12x10-1/2 to 18x25 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, undated, 09/09/1989; Black and red ink sketches on two sheets of white paper and five sheets of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, one initialed and dated 9/9/89 (Map-case 10, Folder 1)
      - Schematic Design Drawings of Tower I., Undated
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, Ink and yellow and red pencil drawing on electrostatic print, 8-1/2x14 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 1)
        - [Elevation], untitled, Red pencil drawing on vellum, 14x24 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 1)
        - [Elevation], three untitled, Ink and colored pencil drawings on one sheet of vellum, 12x12 inches, and three electrostatic prints, 8-1/2x14 to 20-1/2x36 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 1)
      - Conceptual Sketches of Three-Story Academic Wing., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue and black ink sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 18x21 to 18x22-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 12x22 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
        - [Facade Study], untitled, Digital image only of ink sketch on tracing paper
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Ink sketches on two sheets of tracing paper with orange, yellow and gray marker coloring, initialed, 18x18-3/4 & 18x19-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
        - [Facade Studies], untitled, Black, brown and blue ink sketches and drawings on eight sheets of tracing paper, 10-3/4x12 to 12x34-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
      - Schematic Design Drawings of Three-Story Academic Wing., Undated
        - [Elevation], untitled, Ink, pencil and brown pencil drawings on four sheets of vellum, 12x24 to 11-3/4x36 inches, one initialed and dated 11/13/9, and two electrostatic prints, one with red marker coloring, 8-1/2x11 & 11x17 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
      - Conceptual Sketches of Administrative Tower II., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two sheets of tracing paper, 12x12-1/2 & 12x22-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Undated, except as noted
        - [Administration Tower II Elevations] by Birkerts' Associate, untitled, Pencil drawings on two sheets of vellum, 21x20-1/2 & 18-3/4x27-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
        - Presentation Drawings, 11x17-inch photographic prints with colored pantone, except as noted, some dated December 1989
          - Map and Site Plans. Thirteen prints (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
          - Tower Floor Plans, Elevations and Site Sections, 10 prints (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
          - [Academic Wing] Elevations and Sections, Two electrostatic and two photographic prints with pantone (Map-case 10, Folder 2)
  - Riga Cathedral Exhibition of "The Architecture of Gunnar Birkerts," Riga, Latvia, 1989
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, 1989; Electrostatic print of sketch with original ink notations and signature, 11x17 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x20-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
        - "Gunnar Birkerts Arhitektura," Exhibition Poster, 8/5/89-8/31/89; 15-1/2x26 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
  - Grasis Residence, Vail, Colorado, 1990-1994
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with blue and purple marker coloring, 12x14-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with blue, purple and yellow marker coloring, 18x20-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled Ink sketch with notations on vellum graph paper, initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches, 09/21/1990 (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, undated; 11/24/1991; Green and black ink sketches on twelve sheets of tracing paper with marker coloring, two initialed, 9x15-3/4 to 18x28 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Undated, except as noted
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink-on-vellum drawing with pantone overlay, 15x21 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, Pencil and red and green pencil drawing on vellum, 11-1/2x17-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
        - Ground Floor [Plan], 11/30/1991; Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, initialed, 20-3/4x11-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 3)
  - Tiger Stadium Renovation, Detroit, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1991
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Articles, 1991 (Box 10)
      - Letter to Citizens of Michigan, 06/02/1994 (Box 10)
  - Kemper Museum of Contemporary Art & Design, Kansas City Art Institute, Kansas City, Missouri, 1991-1994
    - Project Files
      - Pre-Design Phase Report, 10/30/1991 (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 10)
      - Newspaper and Journal Articles, 1990-1995 (Box 10)
      - Preliminary Floor Plans 08/29/1991, 09/06/1991 Three photographic slides of colored pencil and pen drawings on blue-line prints (Box 10)
      - Public Relations Packet, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, 02/23/1991; Ink sketches on steno pad paper, initialed, 6x9 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 4)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, 03/20/1991; Ink sketches on reverse of "La Valencia Hotel" memo pad paper, 3-1/2x6-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 4)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 08/05/1991; Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 12x24 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 4)
        - [Fountain], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with blue marker coloring, 7-1/2x12 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 4)
        - [Fountain], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with blue marker coloring, 10x12 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 4)
        - Conceptual Design Drawing, Print on vellum exhibition announcement, Kemper Museum of Contemporary Art and Design, Kansas City Art Institute, 6-1/2x13 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 4)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Green and blue ink sketches on ten sheets of yellow tracing paper, 12x18 to 12x23-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 4)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink and blue pencil sketches on eight sheets of white tracing paper with marker coloring, 12x21-1/2 to 18x28 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 4)
      - Kemper Museum Competition Drawings, Ink drawings on tracing paper, initialed, 11x17 inches 3/25/91 except as noted
        - Design Concept (Map-case 10, Folder 5)
        - Grand Atrium Hall, undated; One drawing and one electrostatic print with yellow marker coloring (Map-case 10, Folder 5)
        - Grand Atrium Hall, Permanent Collection Gallery and Changing Exhibition Gallery, One drawing and one electrostatic print with yellow marker coloring (Map-case 10, Folder 5)
        - [Floor Plan], untitled. One drawing and one electrostatic print with yellow marker coloring (Map-case 10, Folder 5)
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Undated, except as noted
        - Gallery Space and Atrium [Section], undated; 08/04/1991; Pencil and colored pencil drawings on two sheets of vellum, 15-1/2x21-1/2 & 17-1/4x22-1/2 inches, one initialed and dated 8/4/91 (Map-case 10, Folder 5)
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, Pencil and red pencil drawings on two sheets of vellum, 12-3/4x21-1/2 & 21-1/2x29-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 5)
  - Pompeo Leoni Private Residential Project, Milan,Italy (unbuilt project), 1992-1994
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 10)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Blue ink sketch on electrostatic print, 11-3/4x16-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on "Specificare Se Interessa" memo paper, initialed, 4x7-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 11/12/1992; Blue ink sketches on "Hotel Cavour, Milano" letter paper, initialed, 7-1/4x10-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Floor Plans], untitled, Ink sketches, one with green marker coloring, on two sheets of tracing paper, 11-1/2x18 & 18x27 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Elevations], untitled, Ink sketches with red marker coloring on two sheets of tracing paper, 12x32 & 12x36 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Elevation], untitled, 12/23/1992; Ink sketch with pencil coloring on electrostatic copy of facsimile print, 11x17 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Elevation and Roof Axonometric], untitled, 12/23/1992; Ink sketches on two facsimile prints, 8-1/2x17-1/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Elevation], untitled, Ink sketch with pencil coloring on tracing paper, initialed, 14-3/4x18 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Roof Development], untitled, 01/06/1993; Green ink sketch on electrostatic print, initialed, 30x42 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
        - [Roof Development], untitled, Blue and black ink sketches on two sheets of tracing paper, 12x19 & 18x20-1/2 inches, three sheets of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, and one sheet of "Hotel Cavour, Milano" letter paper, 7-1/4x10-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Floor Plan and Elevation], untitled, Pencil and colored pencil drawing on electrostatic print taped to pencil and colored pencil drawing on blue-line print, 16x40-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 6)
  - University of Utah J. Willard Marriott Library Addition, Salt Lake City, 1992-1996
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink sketch with green marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x25-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Black and red ink and blue marker sketch on tracing paper, 12x26-1/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink sketch with green marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x25-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Site Plans], untitled, Ink sketches with marker coloring on seven sheets of tracing paper, one initialed, 11-1/4x12 to 12x36-3/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink and colored marker sketch on tracing paper, 12x24-1/4 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x22-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 1993; Ink sketch with yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, initialed, 12x24 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 1993; Ink sketches with yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, initialed, 12x25 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 1993; Ink sketches with yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, initialed, 12x23 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches with marker coloring on tracing paper, 18x28-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x24 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches with marker coloring on tracing paper, initialed, 12x28-1/2 inches (Map-case 10, Folder 7)
  - Library of Michigan, Martha Griffiths Rare Book Room, Lansing, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1993
    - Project Files
      - "Martha W. Griffiths Michigan Rare Book Room," published by the Library of Michigan Foundation,", undated (Box 10)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x18-1/2 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x17-3/4 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 1)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with brown marker coloring on tracing paper, 18x21-1/4 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on four sheets of tracing paper, 12x15-1/4 to 18x25 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 1)
  - Juma al-Majid Center for Culture and Heritage Competition, Dubai, United Arab Emirates (unbuilt project), 1993
    - Project Files
      - Architectural Brief and Competition Rules by Jan Meissner, UNESCO, Paris, 1993 (Box 10)
      - Program Information (Box 10)
      - Gunnar Birkerts and Associates Competition Submission. Conceptual Statements, Architectural Drawings and Cost Estimates, undated (Box 10)
      - Correspondence In and Out, June-October 1993 (Box 10)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on four sheets of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x28 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with marker coloring on tracing paper, 18x37-1/2 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue pencil sketch on tracing paper, 18x37-1/2 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink and blue, orange and green pencil sketch on tracing paper, 18x37 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x24 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, 18x22 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with marker coloring on tracing paper, 18x38 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x32-1/4 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with yellow marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x29 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with blue marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x23-1/4 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch with blue marker coloring on tracing paper, 12x19-3/4 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 14-1/2x18 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 09/27/1993; Ink sketch with marker coloring on tracing paper, initialed, 18-3/4x18 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 10/13/1993; Green ink sketch on tracing paper, initialed, 15-1/2x13 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 2)
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black ink, colored ink and colored pencil sketches, some with marker coloring, on fourteen sheets of tracing paper, 8x18 to 18x43 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 3)
        - [Conceptual Drawing], untitled, 08/29/1993; Green and brown pencil drawing with pencil coloring on tracing paper, 18x32-1/4 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 3)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, Ink drawings with yellow marker coloring on two sheets of tracing paper, one initialed, 12x23 & 12x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 3)
        - [Section], untitled, Blue ink and red pencil drawing with marker and pencil coloring on electrostatic print, 12-1/4x38-1/4 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 3)
        - [Elevation], untitled, Blue and black ink sketches on tracing paper, 9-1/2x18 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 3)
        - [East Elevation and] East-West Section, Black ink, colored ink and pencil drawing with marker coloring on two blue-line prints, 8-1/4x38 & 15x41-1/4 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 3)
        - East Elevation, Black and colored ink and pencil drawing with marker coloring on two blue-line prints, 9-1/4x38 & 9-1/2x41-1/2 inches (Map-case 11, Folder 3)
  - Michigan Technological University Performing Arts Center, Houghton, 1994-2000
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Central Market Master Plan, Riga, Latvia, 1995
    - Architectural Drawings